





Summary

Jump to Section

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

\* 14 years of experience in design and development of windows and web-based applications including 3 years of experience in people management

\* Expertise in Object Oriented Principles, OOAD and Software Architectural and Design Patterns.

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

\* Strong in technologies C#.Net, ASP.Net, ASP.Net M/C, Web Services, Web APIs, ASP.Net Core, WPF, WCF, C++, VC++, MFC, COM/ATL, VB6.0, SQL Server, RabbitMQ, ReatJs, HTML, CSS, Java script, jQeury.

Good understanding of Mcroservices, Docker, Kubernetes, cloud technologies Azure and GCP

\* Business Travel experience to UK and USA Holding valid US-B1 visa.

## **Work Experience**

NCR Corporation India Private Ltd as Tech Lead
 New 2010 to Till Date

May 2016 to Till Date

Organization: NCR

Project: Advanced Store, Emerald

Technologies: C#.Net, ASP.Net, Web APIs, Java Script, SQL Server, ASP.Net Core, Microservices, Kubernetes, Docker, ait

Role: Software Architect

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- \* Worked with customer and project manager to identify the high-level requirements and provide technical direction.
- Provide architectural direction and execution of the customer requirements.
- Developed proof of concept
- SME and Technical local point of contact for the product related quires.
- \* Authored and participated in product architectural review and exploration.
- \* Design and code reviews and sign off for check ins in SVN.
- \* Supporting and mentoring technical leads of respective scrum teams.
- \* Extensively involved in analysis, design and development of major enhancements
- \* Troubleshooting the complex production problems and provide resolution Project: NCR AWS LOGIX NCR Connect, CRM Solutions PROMOTE and RELATE

Technologies: VC++, COM VB6.0, C#, ASP.Net, ASP.Net MvC, WebAPIs, WCF, Web Services, SQL Server 2008

Role: Technical Lead

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- \* Extensively involved in analysis, design and development of major enhancements
- \* Supported development team.
- \* Handling CRM solutions-maintaining the legacy product. Troubleshooting the production problems and resolution.
- \* Implementing the customer's new requirements for the legacy product
- Heavily involved in writing unit tests, code/design/IP docs reviews

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

### AVEVA Software Private Ltd as Team Lead

Project: AVEVA Net, AVEVA Net Gateways, ISM Technologies: C#.Net, ASP.Net, M/C, WPF, XML, C++, COMATL,

Tool: AutoCAD, Microstation, SP3D, PDS3D, TEIGHA ODA

Role: Technical Lead and Manager Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Team management
- Responsible for product deliverable and customer support
- Point of contact for Solution Delivery, Business Development teams, Product Owen and cross teams.
- Providing structure, direction and purpose to team in achieving project goals and meeting the deadlines.
- Support team in Design and implementation of new requirements.

#### NCR Corporation Private Ltd as Senior Software Specialist

Sep 2010 to Mar 2014

Project: NCR AWS LOGIX NCR Connect, CRM Solutions PROMOTE and RELATE

Technologies: VC++, COMVB6.0, C#, ASP.Net, ASP.Net M/C, WebAPIs, WCF, Web Services, SQL Server 2008

Role: Technical Lead

Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Extensively involved in analysis, design and development of major enhancements
- Supported development team.
- Handling CRM solutions-maintaining the legacy product. Troubleshooting the production problems and resolution.
- Implementing the customer's new requirements for the legacy product
- Heavily involved in writing unit tests, code/design/IP docs reviews

# Hexagon (Intergraph), as Senior Software Developer

Oct 2007 to Sep 2010

Project: SP3D (Project Management and Equipment Modules)
Technologies: VC++, COMATL, VB6.0, C#.Net, SQL Server, Oracle

Role: Senior Software Analyst

Responsibilities and Achievements

- Fixing the bugs, maintaining the product, implementing the customer's new requirements in Project Management and Equipment modules.
- Writing the wrappers in .Net to the existing APIs (COM). This made to enhance the knowledge on interoperability. Involved in developing and setting up the Replication/Stream, backup, restore, DB migration in SQL Server/Oracle.
- Involved in developing the tool to convert databases from Oracle to MSSQL and vice versa.

^ Back to Top

#### Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2005

^ Back to Top

## IT Skills

| Skill Name                               | Version Last Used | Experience |
|--|-------------------|------------|
| C#, C, C++, VB6.0, Python, Java Script   |                   |            |
| ASP. Net, MVC, ASP.Net Core, React JS    |                   |            |
| Web APIs, Web Services, WCF, WPF, VC++   |                   |            |
| AutoCAD, MicroStation, NUnit, JIRA       |                   |            |
| VBUnit, MS Test, Coverity, fxCop, NCover |                   |            |
| ANT NANT, Cruise Control, Bamboo,        |                   |            |
| Jenkins, Crucible, VSS, TFS, MKS, SVN,   |                   |            |

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  |             |      |       |       |
| Hindi    |             |      |       |       |
| Telugu   |             |      |       |       |

^ Back to Top

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - IClClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved @ 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.